Scott Harvey

Senior Software Developer Specializing in JavaScript and ColdFusion (202) 744-5379 | scott.harvey@outlook.com | https://www.scottharvey.dev

SUMMARY

I have a recent full stack JavaScript certification in MERN development and over 15 years of experience as a ColdFusion developer. I am looking for a position that allows me to apply the breadth and depth of my experience and skills in an environment that works with modern development frameworks and tools.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT and OTHER SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript: Vanilla, jQuery, JSX, React (Next), VueJS (Nuxt) | HTML | CSS (Bootstrap)

Middleware: ColdFusion | Node (Express) | PHP

Back-End: MongoDB | MS SQL Server | MySQL | Oracle

Tools: Management: Jira | Confluence | Slack | Trello | HubSpot CMS | Pardot | Splunk

Amazon Web Services: Amplify | CloudWatch | Glacier | S3

DevOps: GitHub | Subversion (TortoiseSVN) | Bamboo

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

2019 - present

Providing database and web development support for client projects.

JavaScript (Vanilla / NextJS / MongoDB / VueJS) | HTML | CSS | HubSpot CMS | MS SQL Server | Salesforce Pardot

- **Ethicode.org:** Full-stack development with NextJS and MongoDB on <u>FOOD·E</u> and development and maintenance of https://www.ethicode.org/
- **Autonomy:** Developing and maintaining responsive web pages, mobile application screens, and marketing emails using VueJS, HTML, and CSS for the <u>Cranky Uncle mobile app</u>, <u>Rogue Origin</u>, and <u>Social Solutions</u>.
- Noble Technologies, Inc.: Performing routine data management tasks for the Workers Rights Consortium
 using MS SQL, including database backups, data loads, data validation, and report writing. Assisting with
 database design and modeling, stored procedure writing, and interface support.
- agencyQ: Developing responsive front-end JavaScript, HTML, and CSS modules in HubSpotCMS, including
 featured posts, testimonials, and an image rotator that retrieves data by querying the HubDB database.
 Implementing HTML emailing marketing campaign in Salesforce Pardot.

Association of American Medical Colleges (AAMC)

2016 - 2018

Senior Software Engineer

Developing and maintaining survey and reporting tools serving association members, including medical schools, students, and faculty.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | ColdFusion | Oracle

Providing software design, coding, testing, implementation, documentation, and maintenance on a team of 2 developers, a business analyst, a quality assurance specialist, and a project manager. Performing data analysis, research, and ad hoc reporting according to client needs.

Solution Technology Systems, Inc. (STSI)

2015 - 2016

Senior Software Developer

Developing and maintaining Personal Security System, an automated workflow application that initiates, tracks, and manages background investigations for all Environmental Protection Agency personnel.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | ColdFusion | Oracle

- Providing software coding, testing, implementation, documentation, and maintenance.
- Analyzing, coding, testing, and deploying 40+ change requests to production code, using CMMI processes.
- Identifying business and technical solutions to enable the EPA to optimize business performance.

Council for Logistics Research (CLR)

2003 - 2014

Senior Web Developer

Developing and maintaining software for CLR and its clients including the US Air Force. Managing and mentoring junior developers in a small team. Establishing and maintaining best practices and coding standards for the team.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | ColdFusion | MS SQL Server

Translating business needs into functional requirements and specifications in development of *The Eye*, a robust browser-based enterprise resource planning (ERP) application. Accomplishments include:

- Automating processes including expense reports, purchase orders, purchase requisitions, performance reviews, training requests, time entry and attendance, while adhering to DCAA regulations.
- Consolidating multiple data sources into a single, secure repository for streamlined reporting.

Designing, developing, and implementing software applications for the U.S. Air Force and other clients, such as:

- Enterprise resource planning (ERP) software including resume and skill set tracking
- Event registration and evaluation software
- Content management software, including role-based security, maintenance, and search

agencyQ

Freelance Web Developer

2006 - 2013

Developing and maintaining software for clients of the company.

JavaScript | HTML | ColdFusion | Oracle

- National Institutes of Health (NIH), 2009 2013: Maintaining and developing new functionality for the National Institute on Drug Abuse division's report-creation tool Jennica.
- **Best Cellars, 2007:** Completing an e-commerce migration.

Other Positions

- Web Application Developer, Capital Markets Technology Inc., 2002-2003
- Web Developer, Q Industries, 1999-2002

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Full Stack Web Developer Certificate, Hyperion Dev, 2020
- Amazon Web Services Public Sector Summits, 2020 and 2018
- Adobe ColdFusion Developer Week, 2020
- Certified Expert in ColdFusion, Adobe, 2008
- Hands-On IT Project Management, Project Management Institute, 2005

COURSEWORK (NON-DEGREE)

- Intro to Graphic Design, Corcoran College of Art and Design, 2007
- Carnegie Mellon University, Mellon College of Sciences, 1992 1995